Adam Horvath

adamhorvath.dev | adam.horvath.0827@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/adamhvt | medium.com/@adamhvt

Profile

Experienced Full-Stack Software Engineer with 9 years of experience working with Angular and .NET, leading small teams, designing sofware architecture and frameworks. Looking to obtain the position of Senior Software Engineer in a fast-paced tech environment to further improve professionally and utilise well honed skills in designing and implementing solutions for the web. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a productive team.

Work experience

Phinsys Ltd (London, Insurtech)

2022 - Senior Software Engineer

Working on the reimplementation of the flagship data warehousing product. Responsible for delivering key features: a diagramming tool for defining ETL processes, code editors with custom language features, bespoke and standard form controls using Angular and other features spanning from database to frontend.

Technologies used: Angular 14+, Nx, .Net 7+, SQL Server and Azure.

This is Motif Ltd (London, Market Research)

2020-2022 Software Engineer 2022-2022 Development Manager

Instrumental role in designing and implementing software solutions for delivering and presenting market research data. Responsibilities included designing and implementing features and modules for multiple client facing reporting and content management systems and an internal project management system. In 2022 I became responsible for managing software development within the company.

Highlighted responsibilities and achievements:

- Lead developer of the flagship content management and reporting system: I was responsible for managing feature and change requests for the flagship content management system.
 Thechnologies used: Angular 10-14, .Net 6, SQL Server, Cosmos DB, DevOps and Azure.
- <u>Lead developer of a sample processing workflow system:</u> I was responsible for implementing optimisations and new features for a system which is used for processing survey sample files with high throughput using Azure Functions.
 - Technologies used: Angular 10-14, .Net 6, Azure Functions, SQL Server, Cosmos DB, DevOps and Azure.
- Full software redesign of an internal project management system: Managed to improve code quality,
 maintainability and extensibility by a large margin. The project resulted in significant performance and UX improvements, highly improving the efficiency of project management.
 - Technologies used: Angular 14, .Net6, SQL Server, MongoDB.

L&M Solutions Consulting (Budapest, Consulting)

2015-2017 Part-time Software Engineer 2017-2019 Project Manager, Software Engineer

Worked on several large enterprise web solutions as a full-stack engineer and as project manager on multiple others. Altogether I was involved in the whole software delivery lifecycle, including requirement analysis, system design, hands on coding, managing development and project progress, presenting results to stakeholders, documentation and deploying solutions.

Clients included a major Hungarian bank, a German automotive company, Central European oil and gas supply companies among others.

Adam Horvath

adamhorvath.dev | adam.horvath.0827@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/adamhvt | medium.com/@adamhvt

Highlighted projects:

<u>Lead developer for an Automotive manufacturing support system:</u> Architected and led the development of an automotive manufacturing quality test management system with complex user interfaces and workflows for one of the major automotive brands. Worked productively with clients to understand requirements and user needs, was able to keep balance between speed of delivery and quality, while meeting high level security standards.

Technologies used: Angular 4+, .Net Framework, SQL Server

- Intranet portal for one of the largest banks in Central Europe: Developed several software components for
 creating, targeting and consuming news articles, recommendations and social network features using
 SharePoint's SPFx and React with TypeScript. I was able to learn React within a very limited timespan and build
 high quality, highly scalable applications matching high UI/UX standards.
 Technologies used: React, SharePoint, SPFx
- Full-stack application framework to bolster delivering projects on a fast pace: Architected and lead the
 development of a front-end framework as part of a full-stack framework. I built a reusable component system
 using Angular that comprises of multiple high quality components, services and modules. This framework has
 been used for delivering numerous solutions of small to large scale.

Technologies used: AngularJS-Angular 4+, .Net Framework, SharePoint, SQL Server

Skills

Technical skills

- Angular, TypeScript, JavaScript, CSS, Sass
- .Net, .Net Core, C#
- SQL Server, MongoDB, CosmosDB
- Azure, DevOps
- Agile Development, Web Application Design and Architecture, Responsive and Adaptive UI Design
- Also familiar with React, SharePoint, MongoDB, CosmosDB

Soft skills

- Commitment to delivering value
- Active learner, maintaining a technical blog
- Team-oriented: Making the most out of collaboration, can give constructive, beneficial feedback
- · Ability to communicate engineering concepts to technical and nontechnical stakeholders
- Ability to handle multiple workstreams and prioritize accordingly
- Good balance between quality and speed of delivery

Education

Óbuda University, Budapest

Bachelor of Science in Engineering Information Technologist (2017)

Interests

Software Design and Architecture, Software Security, UX, Science